# **SON VAN NGUYEN**

VinAI Research, Ha Noi, Viet Nam.

Homepage: sonpeter.github.io

(+84) 965 277 261 ◊ sonnguyenkstn@gmail.com

#### RESEARCH INTEREST

My core research focuses on developing interpretable and scalable algorithms for machine learning models. I am particularly excited about practical and flexible approximate inference methods applied in complex settings such as probabilistic deep learning, hierarchical latent models, large-scale online learning.

## **EDUCATION**

# Ha Noi University of Science and Technology (HUST)

Ha Noi, Viet Nam

Master of Data Science, Master of Research degree
 Oct 2019 - Apr 2021

 Thesis title: "Improving Bayesian inference in deep neural networks with Variational Structured Dropout"
 CPA: 3.84/4.0

Bachelor of Information Technology, Program of Talented Engineers
 Aug 2014 - Jun 2019

 Thesis title: "An effective Bayesian approach for discovering hidden semantics from data streams"
 CPA: 3.50/4.0 (rank 2/21 in the talented class)

Phan Boi Chau High School for the Gifted Students, Specialized Math Class

Nghe An, Viet Nam Aug 2011 - Jun 2014

### **EXPERIENCES**

## VinAI Research (www.vinai.io)

AI Research Resident

Ha Noi, Viet Nam Aug 2020-present

- Main research topics: Bayesian Deep Learning, Deep Generative Models
- Advisor: Dr. Nhat Ho (Assistant Professor at UT, Austin)
- Knowledge gained: Advances in Bayesian Deep Learning (gradient-based MCMC, Variational Inference with dependence structure, principles of uncertainty estimation), Deep Generative Models (VAEs, GANs, Normalizing Flows, applications of Optimal Transport)

## **Data Science Laboratory (HUST)**

Research Assistant

Ha Noi, Viet Nam Feb 2019 - Aug 2020

- Main research topics: Probabilistic Graphical Model, Online and Continual Learning
- Advisor: Dr Khoat Than (Associate Professor at HUST)
- Knowledge gained: Fundamental Machine Learning and Deep Learning, Topic models, Bayesian inference, Variational Approximation

Teaching Assistant Feb 2020 - Jun 2020

• Machine Learning and Data Mining course

## Viettel Network Technology R&D Center

Department of Data Science

Ha Noi, Viet Nam Jun 2018 - Jun 2019

• Projects: analyze the consumer behavior in telecommunication of millions of users, develop recommendation algorithms for promotions

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- **1. Son Nguyen**, Duong Nguyen, Khai Nguyen, Nhat Ho, Khoat Than, Hung Bui, "Structured Dropout Variational Inference for Bayesian Neural Networks," *Under review*
- **2.** Khai Nguyen, **Son Nguyen**, Nhat Ho, Tung Pham, Hung Bui, "Distributional Sliced-Wasserstein and Applications to Generative Modeling," *International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2021*
- **3.** Ha Nguyen, Hoang Pham, **Son Nguyen**, Linh Ngo, Khoat Than, "Adaptive Infinite Dropout for Noisy and Sparse Data Streams," *Under review Machine Learning journal*
- **4. Son Nguyen**, Tung Nguyen, Linh Ngo, Khoat Than, "Infinite Dropout for training Bayesian models from data streams," *IEEE International Conference on Big Data (Big Data) 2019*

## **AWARDS AND RECOGNITIONS**

1. Scholarship of the Domestic Master Program of Vingroup Innovation Foundation, VINIF (\$5,000)	2019
2. Best Thesis Award, Best Presentation Award for undergraduate student	2019
3. Third Prize in the Scientific Research Student Conference, HUST	2019
4. Scholarship for students with good academic records, HUST	2015, 2017
<b>5.</b> Vietnam Mathematics Olympiad for university students (VMS) (First Prize in Calculus, Second Prize in Algebra)	2015, 2016
<b>6.</b> Second prize in Vietnam Mathematical Olympiad (VMO) for high school students	2014

7. Scholarship (for high school students) of the National Program for the Development of Mathematics of Vietnam Institute for Advanced Study in Mathematics, VIASM 2013, 2014

# **EDUCATIONAL ACTIVITIES**

- Book: Olympic mathematical topics for gifted students, 2 volumes, Vietnam National University Press, Ha Noi.
   Nguyen Dinh Thanh Cong, Nguyen Van Huong, Nguyen Duy Hung, Tran Tri Kien, Nguyen Van Son, Le Nhat, Tran Bao Trung
   Jul 2016
- **2.** Member of GSTT Group (a nonprofit educational organization), lead refresher courses and consolidate the knowledge for high school students

  Oct 2014 Oct 2015

# SPECIALIZED SKILLS

# **Programming skills:**

• Proficient: Python (PyTorch, numpy, pandas, scikit-learn)

• Familiar: C, JAVA, LATEX